<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tutorial on blag</title><link>http://avi.im/blag/categories/tutorial/</link><description>Recent content in tutorial on blag</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 22:20:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://avi.im/blag/categories/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>When is my Cake Day?</title><link>http://avi.im/blag/2015/kekday/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2015 22:20:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://avi.im/blag/2015/kekday/</guid><description>Reddit gives all the user info in a handy JSON at this URL: https://www.reddit.com/user/&amp;lt;username here&amp;gt;/about.json
example: https://www.reddit.com/user/spez/about.json
The created_utc field in data is the date of user&amp;rsquo;s registration aka Cake Day in unix epoch format (in UTC) and we can easily convert that to readable format:
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; import time &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; time.strftime(&amp;#34;%D&amp;#34;, time.gmtime(1118030400)) &amp;#39;06/06/05&amp;#39; Using Python Requests, we can turn this into a handy function:
import time import requests def get_my_cake_day(username): url = &amp;#34;https://www.</description></item><item><title>How I Am Maintaining Multiple Emails For Git On A Same Machine</title><link>http://avi.im/blag/2015/multiple-git-emails/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 22:20:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://avi.im/blag/2015/multiple-git-emails/</guid><description>Every git commit is associated with two important data: your name and email. I don&amp;rsquo;t want my personal email address associated with work related git commits and vice versa. First, to set the git email address system wide, you would run following:
$git config --global user.email &amp;quot;your_global@email.com&amp;quot; $git config --global user.name &amp;quot;Your Name&amp;quot; and every commits will have above info. To set the email address for individual repo, just drop the global.</description></item><item><title>Flashing Asus-WRT Merlin by XVortex on NetGear NightHawk R7000</title><link>http://avi.im/blag/2015/asus-wrt-merlin-on-netgear-r7000/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2015 22:20:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://avi.im/blag/2015/asus-wrt-merlin-on-netgear-r7000/</guid><description>Note: There are many ways to achieve this and in this tutorial I follow two flash method.
Preparation: This guide assumes you are on stock firmware. If you are already on DD WRT or Tomato, ignore step 2 of procedure. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether you are on Windows, Linux or Mac. Everything happens in browser Make sure you are connected to the router over one of WAN ports It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter which firmware version you are currently on.</description></item><item><title>Install Windows 8 UEFI on Legacy BIOS with Clover (and Dual boot with Yosemite)</title><link>http://avi.im/blag/2014/install-uefi-windows-yosemite-dualboot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2014 16:20:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://avi.im/blag/2014/install-uefi-windows-yosemite-dualboot/</guid><description>In this tutorial I am going to explain how to install Windows 8 on a Legacy BIOS in UEFI mode (Yes! It&amp;rsquo;s possible!!) using Clover and dual boot with Yosemite. Technically this tutorial should work for Windows 7 and Mavericks also, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried.
This tutorial was originally written for Insanely Mac Forums. Check the original thread.
What you get? You have a machine with Legacy BIOS and at the end of tutorial, you would have Yosemite OS X and Windows 8.</description></item><item><title>Installing Transmission (remote and CLI) client on Raspberry Pi</title><link>http://avi.im/blag/2013/installing-transmission-raspberry-pi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2013 10:20:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://avi.im/blag/2013/installing-transmission-raspberry-pi/</guid><description>I have found Transmission to be best client to run on Raspberry Pi. In this tutorial I will explain how to install Transmission and access it using it&amp;rsquo;s web interface over browser.
Though this tutorial is for Raspberry Pi, it should work for any computer running Debian flavour.
First run these commands to update and upgrade the packages you have installed.
sudo apt-get update sudo apt-get upgrade sudo apt-get install transmission-daemon Create a directory where you will be saving the downloads.</description></item></channel></rss>